role-editor.com 2019-09-04

# Privacy Policy - User Role Editor

This privacy policy describes how role-editor.com uses and protects any information that you give us. We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. If you provide us with personal information through role-editor.com you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, role-editor.com collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. role-editor.com’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how role-editor.com’s visitors use it.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to role-editor.com choose to interact with role-editor.com in ways that require role-editor.com to gather personally-identifying information. For example, we ask visitors who buy membership to provide a username and email address.

In each case, role-editor.com collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with role-editor.com. role-editor.com does not disclose personally-identifying information. Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities, like purchasing a User Role Editor Pro membership.

role-editor.com does collect or/and store any financial information. role-editor.com uses [PayPal](https://paypal.com/) as a payment gateway. Any personal information you provide for the payment is processed/stored by PayPal on its own resources.

All of the information that is collected on role-editor.com will be handled in accordance with GDPR legislation.

role-editor.com also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. role-editor.com does not use IP addresses to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information to other parties.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

role-editor.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of project administrators, employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on role-editor.com’s behalf or to provide services available through role-editor.com, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using role-editor.com, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

role-editor.com will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to project administrators, employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations, as described above, role-editor.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, if you give permission to have your information shared, or when role-editor.com believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of role-editor.com, third parties, or the public at large.

If you are a registered user of a role-editor.com website and have supplied your email address, role-editor.com may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with role-editor.com and User Role Editor Pro. We primarily use our blog to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum.

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. role-editor.com takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Use of personal information

We use the information you provide to register for an account.

We will not sell or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

We would like to send you email with information about User Role Editor Pro critical security fixes and/or news. If you have consented to this kind of information, you may opt out later.

You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you with information about User Role Editor Pro. If you no longer wish to be contacted with information about User Role Editor Pro, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.

## Legal grounds for processing personal information

We rely on one or more of the following processing conditions:

  * our legitimate interests in the effective delivery of information and services to you;
  * explicit consent that you have given;
  * legal obligations.

## Access to data

You have the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all your personal information, please follow the instructions at the end of this policy.

role-editor.com user accounts can be edited by following these steps:  
1) Visit https://www.role-editor.com/wp-login.php, and then enter your username and password.  
2) You can access your user account page after successful login by this link https://www.role-editor.com/membership-account.  
3) Click the “Edit” link next to the “My Account” title to open your user profile where you can edit any information you have input earlier.

## Retention of personal information

We will retain your personal information on our systems only for as long as we need to, for the success of the role-editor.com project. We keep contact information (such as mailing list information) until a user unsubscribes or requests that we delete that information from our live systems. If you choose to unsubscribe from a mailing list, we may keep certain limited information about you so that we may honor your request.

role-editor.com will not delete personal data from logs or records necessary to the operation, development, or archives of the role-editor.com project.

role-editor.com stores information about your purchases: date, subject, sum, PayPal transaction ID.

## Rights in relation to your information

You may have certain rights under data protection law in relation to the personal information we hold about you. In particular, you may have a right to:

  * request a copy of personal information we hold about you;
  * ask that we update the personal information we hold about you, or independently correct such personal information that you think is incorrect or incomplete;
  * ask that we delete personal information that we hold about you from live systems, or restrict the way in which we use such personal information;
  * object to our processing of your personal information; and/or
  * withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal information (to the extent such processing is based on consent and consent is the only permissible basis for processing).

If you would like to exercise these rights or understand if these rights apply to you, please follow the instructions at the end of this Privacy statement.

## Third Party Links

Our website may contain links to other websites provided by third parties not under our control. When following a link and providing information to a 3rd-party website, please be aware that we are not responsible for the data provided to that third party. This privacy policy only applies to the role-editor.com, so when you visit other websites, even when you click on a link posted on role-editor.com, you should read their own privacy policies.

## Aggregated Statistics

role-editor.com may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its website. For instance, role-editor.com may reveal how many times a particular version of User Role Editor Pro was downloaded or report about quantity of the active subscribers. However, role-editor.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described in this policy.

## Cookies

Additionally, information about how you use our website is collected automatically using “cookies”. Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, role-editor.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and at role-editor.com’s sole discretion. role-editor.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

## Contact

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us via [Contact Form](https://www.role-editor.com/contact-us "Contact Us") or emailing to support@role-editor.com.
